erols.com 2017-06-15

# RCN Privacy Policy

### RCN Privacy Policy 

RCN understands how important personal privacy is to you and we are committed to fully protect your rights. We want our customers to be aware of what information RCN collects and how it is handled. This statement discloses RCN's privacy practices, including an explanation of which personal information about RCN's customers is collected, how the information is used, with whom the information may be shared, how the customer can correct any inaccuracies in the information, and your rights and our responsibilities under applicable privacy laws. 

**As a customer of RCN, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy, and revisions made to the Privacy Policy from time to time (see VI. Revision of This Policy), unless and until you terminate your RCN services.  
**

**Summary**

As set forth more fully below, RCN may collect and use Personally Identifiable Information, including CPNI, as defined herein, to the extent permitted by applicable law: 

  * for the stated purpose for which such information is gathered 
  * for marketing, sales, and customer retention purposes 
  * for billing and collection purposes 
  * for provisioning, installing, auditing and maintaining service 
  * for legal, financial, accounting and tax record keeping 
  * for protection of RCN’s network and subscribers against fraud, abuse and unlawful use 
  * for other RCN business purposes associated with its services 
  * for meeting requirements imposed by governmental authorities 

RCN does not request personal information from children; therefore, we ask parents or guardians to oversee their children’s use of RCN’s services, and not to provide any personal information pertaining to children. 

**I. PERSONALLY/NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION & AGGREGATED DATA **

To provide reliable, quality services RCN must gather and collect certain information, both personally identifiable and aggregated, regarding its customers and potential customers. 

**A. Personally Identifiable Information and Customer Proprietary Network Information**

Some of the information that RCN collects is "personally identifiable," meaning the information relates to a specific, identifiable individual. Personally Identifiable Information includes, but is not limited to: 

  * names (and spouses’ names) 
  * street addresses 
  * telephone numbers 
  * identification numbers (such as driver's license and/or social security numbers) 
  * credit card numbers and credit information 
  * account numbers and account information 
  * log files, URLs, IP addresses, information collected via “Cookies,” and MAC addresses or other equipment identifiers, when associated with individuals’ names or account information 

A specific type of Personally Identifiable Information that RCN may collect and use if you are a telephone customer is Customer Proprietary Network Information (“CPNI”), which is telephone account information collected in connection with the telephone services you purchase from RCN. CPNI may include: 

  * how many telecommunications services you have 
  * the types of lines you buy 
  * technical characteristics of your service 
  * class of service (business or residential) 
  * where, when, and to whom you place a call 
  * the related billing for these services 

Unless you have requested an unlisted or unpublished number, CPNI does not include “subscriber list information,” that is, your name, address, and telephone number included in directories. As indicated above, however, such information is considered Personally Identifiable Information. 

**B. Non-Personally Identifiable Information/Aggregated Data**

RCN also collects and uses Non-Personally Identifiable Information, including Aggregated Data, which does not identify individual customers. Non-Personally Identifiable Information can include log files, URLs, IP addresses, information collected via “Cookies,” and MAC addresses or other equipment identifiers when not associated with individuals’ names or account information. Aggregated Data is data associated with categories of service or customers that does not contain specific details about the identity of the person to whom it relates. 

**II. RCN'S COLLECTION OF INFORMATION**

As explained below, in rendering its services, RCN may collect Personally Identifiable Information and CPNI during the course of: 

  * marketing and sales 
  * initiating service or changing customer accounts 
  * customer service 
  * operation of RCN web sites 
  * creation and maintenance of business records 
  * operating, maintaining, and protecting the security of the RCN network and related equipment 

**A. Marketing and Sales/Initiating Service/Customer Service**

RCN is actively engaged in face-to-face sales, direct marketing, telemarketing, and marketing and sales via the Internet (eCommerce). Personally Identifiable Information, including CPNI, is collected in the course of checking customers’ credit and eligibility for service, initiating and provisioning service, maintaining service, billing for service, providing customer service, marketing new and additional services to customers, and customer retention efforts. RCN may monitor and/or record telephone calls placed to an RCN customer service and support center for quality assurance and training purposes. Third party verification services, which are independent from RCN, often record follow-up calls to verify sales made by RCN telemarketers. RCN also keeps records relating to contacts with RCN customer service and support representatives, customer complaints, complaints about customer behavior, and reports of violations of our policies or agreements associated with your account. RCN keeps track of service tickets that are opened in response to reports of service disruption, and RCN customer service representatives may make notes in your account whenever you place a service call. 

**B. RCN Web Sites**

To help make our website more responsive to the needs of our users and visitors, RCN.com makes use of a standard feature of browser software called a "Cookie." “Cookies” are small text files that enable a continuous connection to web sites, making it easier to visit pages within a web site without having to download the web site each time. Cookies are meant to assist the user to visit a web site in a seamless fashion. RCN.com uses Cookies to help us tailor our website to your needs, to deliver a better, more personalized service, and to remember certain choices you’ve made so you don’t have to re-enter them. 

Some of the RCN web sites allow customers to perform self-care on their accounts or to engage in eCommerce. When the customer successfully logs into the RCN web server, it will place a Cookie containing an identifier on the customer's hard disk. As the customer transmits each subsequent page of information to the server, the server will ask the individual's computer for the Cookie to confirm the individual's identity without requiring the individual to login each time. The Cookie will not run any programs or cause malfunction of a computer. The Cookie will only be read by RCN's web server and used to expedite customer login to the RCN web site. 

The Cookies RCN.com uses don’t directly identify visitors to or users of our website as particular persons. Rather, they contain information sufficient to simplify and improve a visitor’s or user’s experience on our website. For example, RCN.com may use session-based Cookies to track the pages on our website visited by our users. RCN.com can build a better website if it’s known which pages our users are visiting and how often. 

Cookies may also be placed on your hard disk by web sites that are not operated by RCN. RCN is not responsible for Cookies placed or provided by non-RCN websites. (See V. Links to Other Web Sites). 

RCN may also use one or more advertising network providers and/or other audience segmenting technology providers to help present advertisements or other content on this website and other websites that display RCN advertisements. These providers use Cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies on your computer or mobile or other device to serve you advertisements or content tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other websites you have visited. It also helps determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement or content before, which helps avoid sending you duplicate ads. In doing so, these providers collect non-personally identifiable information such as your browser type, your operating system, web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other click stream data. When you visit RCN’s website, these providers may use Cookies or web beacons to note which product and service descriptions your browser visited. When you are presented with RCN advertisements on other websites, RCN.com or these providers may use that information to select advertisements related to your interests. This is intended to provide you with an additional opportunity to look at RCN offerings that may be of interest to you. The use of Cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these providers is subject to their own privacy policies, not RCN’s privacy policy for this website. 

The "help" portion on the toolbar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new Cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you are to receive a new Cookie, or how to disable Cookies altogether. However, as Cookies allow your user experience to be enhanced, and expedite login in RCN's web sites, RCN.com recommends that you leave them turned on. 

**C. Business Records**

RCN keeps business records that contain Personally Identifiable Information, including CPNI. Our records include information about the account holder and other authorized users on the account; account history, including information related to credit, billing, payment, damage and security deposits, initiation and provisioning of service, changes in service, maintenance and repairs, complaints, and contacts with customer service; the services and service options you have chosen, including call detail information, if you are a telephone customer, the video services you order, if you are a cable customer, and information regarding your Internet usage, if you are a high-speed Internet service customer; and the equipment you have connected to the RCN network or that is capable of connecting to the RCN network. RCN also keeps records relating to complaints about customer behavior, and reports of violations of our policies or agreements. We also keep records of research concerning subscriber satisfaction, viewing habits, and network usage, which are obtained from subscriber interviews, questionnaires, and passive monitoring of the RCN network. Additionally, if you rent your home, we may have a record of whether landlord permission was required prior to installing our wiring and equipment, as well as your landlord’s name and address. 

**D. Network Operation**

RCN's cable television headend equipment collects data relating to signal quality and programming selections, including pay-per-view and video on demand selections, for billing purposes. RCN may electronically test the video delivery system from time-to-time to determine whether customers are being properly billed for the cable service they receive. Digital cable television service is delivered with an Interactive Programming Guide operated by and licensed from Aptiv Digital, Inc. (“Aptiv”). Aptiv provides RCN the capability to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information and Aggregated Data about viewing patterns through the use of its Interactive Programming Guide. Without appropriate written or electronic consent from you, pursuant to Section 631 of the Communications Act of 1984, as amended [47 U.S.C. 551] (the “Communications Act”), we cannot collect Personally Identifiable Information over the cable system unless it is necessary to provide a cable or other service you have requested or to determine if you are being properly billed for the services you are receiving. 

RCN's telephone switch equipment automatically collects data (call records) relating to the originating and terminating telephone numbers involved in each telephone call carried over the RCN network, the date, time, and duration of the call, and the applicable billing rate, among other types of information that allow RCN to work with other telephone and wireless networks to route a call and to permit billing of the call. 

RCN’s servers, and servers connected to the RCN network by authorized third parties for data collection purposes, also collect certain information. As is common practice in our industry, RCN may use web caching software on its network to ensure optimum performance for our customers. Such software by its nature captures Internet Protocol and URL information to a log file. The RCN network also automatically logs certain information, such as application usage and type. Such logs generally are maintained on RCN's secured servers and/or the secured servers of authorized third parties as long as is necessary to fulfill a legitimate business or law enforcement need. Typically, information collected by servers connected to the RCN network is maintained as Non-Personally Identifiable Information and/or Aggregated Data. However, this information may become Personally Identifiable Information if and when RCN associates the information with a particular customer’s account for marketing, customer retention, or network security and reliability purposes. This data may also be used to protect the security of RCN’s network, to prevent network intrusions from viruses and worms, and for advertising purposes. Specifically, RCN and certain third parties authorized by RCN have the ability to monitor all network traffic destined to and from any connected device attached to RCN’s network. However, authorized third parties, which may collect this information for marketing, customer retention, product development, or advertising purposes, do not receive any Personally Identifiable Information from RCN regarding RCN’s customers, but rather collect the data on an anonymous and/or aggregated basis. In most cases, network traffic monitoring is restricted to viewing source/destination addresses, and the content of the transaction is not viewed. However, the information collected may include URLs of web sites you have visited and the content of any unencrypted e-mail or other communications sent by or to you. Such data, when stored, is protected by industry-standard security practices. RCN technical support also may remotely query your cable modem and, if you request during a contact with our customer service department, your computer, for information to remotely troubleshoot and to assist in diagnosing a problem that might affect the computer attached via cable modem to the RCN network. 

Customer On-Line Communications: RCN does not actively monitor the content of any on-line communication (electronic mail (e-mail), chat conversations, instant messages, or web postings), but may use an automated system to randomly audit such transmittals to protect RCN’s network from viruses, worms, and excessive spam. RCN takes the privacy and security of its customer’s on-line communications very seriously. RCN will view the content of online communications only when it is necessary to protect the security of RCN’s network or ensure system reliability. For example, if our automated system detects unusual levels of activity to or from your computer, RCN personnel may view the content of those transmissions to determine if the network traffic is the result of a virus, worm, excessive spam, or violation of our Internet Access Agreement. 

You should be aware that, should you disclose any personally identifiable or sensitive information while engaged in on-line communications, there is the risk of having the person(s) to whom or sites to which the information is addressed collect and use it. One should also be mindful that people might be logged into a public chat room without your knowledge. RCN assumes no responsibility for or control over any such third persons. Information posted in chat rooms and newsgroups that RCN operates are deleted on average every third day to clear posted messages. E-mail is deleted from RCN's server once it is downloaded to a customer's computer. 

**III. PRIVACY AND USE OF INFORMATION**

At RCN, the privacy and security of your account is very important to us. That is why we have taken measures to protect the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information and CPNI in compliance with the federal laws and FCC regulations that govern use and disclosure of customer information. The uses to which your information may be put are discussed below, together with the security measures RCN has implemented for all customer accounts. 

**A. Account Passwords/Customer Authentication**

To better protect all of your account information and allow us to provide you the best quality customer service, you must establish a password and two backup security questions for your account when you establish service. If your account does not have a password and backup security questions, you will be asked to provide them. The password and backup security questions may not be based on readily available biographical information or account information. Readily available biographical information is information drawn from the customer’s life history and may include, for example, social security number, or the last four digits of that number, mother’s maiden name, home address or date of birth. Account information includes things such as the customer’s account number, telephone number associated with the account, or the bill’s amount. Federal law also requires RCN to utilize a password authentication method when communicating with customers on-line or by telephone regarding their telephone accounts where the customer seeks call detail or other account information. Under certain circumstances, RCN may have separate contractual arrangements with its business customers governing authentication methods and protection of the business customer’s telephone account information. 

**B. Cable Television Customer Privacy**

As a subscriber to cable service or other services provided by RCN, you are entitled under Section 631 of the Federal Cable Communications Policy Act of 1984, as amended (the “Communication Act”) to know the limitations imposed upon cable operators in the collection and disclosure of personally identifiable subscriber information, the type of personally identifiable information collected, how subscriber information is used, under what conditions it is disclosed, the period during which it is maintained, and the right of subscribers concerning such information and its disclosure. RCN may use Personally Identifiable Information to help make sure you are being properly billed for the services you receive, to send you pertinent information regarding your cable services, to improve the quality of the services we provide, and for tax, legal, and accounting purposes. Specifically, the information in our cable records is used to sell, install, maintain, and disconnect cable services, as well as improve marketing and program decisions, to mail related materials, to ensure compliance with relevant law and contractual provisions, and to answer questions from subscribers. The types of persons to whom information about you as a cable customer may be disclosed in the course of our business include the employees of RCN and RCN’s related legal entities, agents, legal counsel, repair and installation subcontractors, sales representatives, accountants, billing and collection services, program guide distributors, mail houses, program suppliers, consumer and market research firms, franchising authorities, and authorized representatives. Personally Identifiable Information is disclosed to persons with an equity interest in legal entities related to RCN when they have a legal right to inspect our books and records. Information for billing purposes and program guide mailings is generally provided on a monthly basis. Information for other purposes is provided as it is needed. 

We will maintain information about you as a cable subscriber as long as it is necessary for our business purposes. This period of time lasts as long as you are a subscriber and up to 15 additional years so that we can comply with tax and accounting requirements. 

Unless you object or unless state or local law provides to the contrary, the Communications Act allows us to disclose information to others, including advertisers and direct mail or telemarketers for non-cable related purposes, including product advertising, direct marketing and research. Disclosure for such purposes is limited to your name, address and the particular services to which you subscribe, but cannot include the extent of your viewing or use of a particular service or the nature of any transaction you may make over the cable system. We may provide names and addresses of cable subscribers to third parties. If you wish to have us remove your name from such lists, please write us at RCN Telecom Services, LLC, 650 College Road East, Suite 3100, Princeton, NJ 08540 or telephone 1.800.RING.RCN. We will then not make your name and address available for such non-cable purposes. 

Aptiv provides RCN the capability to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information and Aggregated Data about viewing patterns on RCN’s digital cable television service through the use of its Interactive Programming Guide. This information is used by RCN to measure subscriber use and satisfaction and improve services and marketing. 

Other than information provided to governmental taxing or regulatory authorities in furtherance of our legitimate business activities, RCN shall not make Personally Identifiable Information regarding its cable customers available to government authorities in the absence of an appropriate court order entered after a court proceeding. At such a court proceeding, Federal law requires the governmental entity to offer clear and convincing evidence that the subject of the information is reasonably suspected of engaging in criminal activity and that the information sought would be material evidence in the case. The subject of the information must be afforded the opportunity to appear and contest the governmental entity’s claims. In addition, pursuant to an administrative subpoena, state welfare agencies may obtain the names and addresses of individuals as they appear in the customer records of cable television companies with respect to those who owe, or are owed, welfare support. Such information may be obtained without a court order and does not require that a subscriber be given notice of and the opportunity to contest the disclosure. 

You have a right to inspect our records that contain information about you as a cable customer and correct any errors in such information. If you wish to inspect our records, please contact your local RCN business office. Please notify us in writing 30 days in advance and an appointment will be arranged promptly during our regular business hours. Additionally, as a cable subscriber, the Communications Act provides you with a cause of action for damages, attorney’s fees and costs in Federal District Court should you believe that any of the limitations on the collection, disclosure, and retention of Personally Identifiable Information have been violated by us. 

**C. Telephone Customer Privacy**

The Communications Act also gives you a right to confidentiality of your CPNI, and requires us to protect the privacy of that information. RCN, or its agents and affiliates, may use, disclose or permit access to your CPNI without notifying you, to provide, install, and repair the services you have ordered, for billing and collection, for emergency services, and for protection of our network and our subscribers against fraud, abuse, and unlawful use. RCN also may be compelled to disclose CPNI or other Personally Identifiable Information in compliance with government taxing or regulatory authorities or pursuant to law enforcement directives or court order. 

From time to time we may have the opportunity to offer you related products and services that will better meet your needs by using information about the telephone services you have already purchased from RCN. Use of your CPNI for this purpose may enhance our ability to make you aware of new or alternate products and services that are tailored to your needs. We may also share CPNI, without your prior consent, with RCN’s affiliates and agents for administrative and marketing purposes, but only for communications-related services. RCN, and its agents or affiliates, are permitted to use CPNI to market new communications services to which you do not currently subscribe, but only after providing you with written or electronic notice and the opportunity to “opt-out” of such use. Under these circumstances, it is assumed that if you do not affirmatively instruct RCN not to use or disclose CPNI for such use, you have consented to the use of your CPNI for these purposes. RCN is required to provide you with this “opt-out” notice biennially, and will wait 30 days after providing such notice before assuming you have approved the use or disclosure of CPNI. Your decision to restrict our use of your CPNI is free of charge and will not affect the service you receive from RCN. If you wish to “opt-out” of RCN’s use of your CPNI, please notify RCN, in writing, at RCN Telecom Services, LLC, 650 College Road East, Suite 3100, Princeton, NJ 08540, or e-mail to [phone@rcn.com ](mailto:phone@rcn.com), or call us at 1.800.RING.RCN. You may contact us at any time in the future to restrict the use of your CPNI. If you elect not to restrict the use of your CPNI, RCN may use it for any of the purposes described above. 

Except as otherwise indicated herein, and as required under applicable law, RCN will provide you with prior written, electronic, or oral notice and obtain your affirmative consent before sharing your CPNI with joint venture partners and independent contractors for marketing purposes. 

You may receive marketing information from RCN even if you restrict RCN’s use of your CPNI. These materials are developed without use of CPNI. 

In the event that there is an unauthorized disclosure of your CPNI, RCN is required to notify law enforcement of the breach of your CPNI. Under federal law, RCN is required to wait at least seven (7) business days after notifying law enforcement officials before it can notify you of such a breach. Relevant investigating agencies may direct RCN to wait even longer prior to providing you with notice of the breach of CPNI. 

Unless you have requested an unlisted or unpublished number, RCN may release your name, address, and telephone number for listing in directories or for directory assistance services, including to unaffiliated third parties. 

**D. High Speed Internet Access Service Customer Privacy**

RCN is committed to protection of any Personally Identifiable Information, including CPNI, captured or stored on its network. RCN secures such information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure using industry-standard methods such as firewalls, encryption, and system access controls. Our network security practices are regularly reviewed against industry best practices by internal staff and independent third parties. However, as no computer or network-based product exists that can provide "perfect security", RCN cannot guarantee your information is completely risk-free. Furthermore, you should be aware that any information you include in a message you post to a chat room, newsgroup, or other public posting area generally is available to anyone with Internet access. (See II.D. Customer On-Line Communications). 

Non-Personally Identifiable Information and Aggregated Data collected via RCN’s network, as described in Section II.D above, is used by RCN and third parties: 

  * to understand how the RCN network is operating and being used 
  * to monitor quality of service 
  * to analyze aggregate customer behavior to assist RCN in improving and marketing its services 
  * for RCN marketing, sales, and consumer retention efforts 
  * for third party marketing and advertising purposes 

RCN may use Personally Identifiable Information or CPNI, collected via RCN’s network, as described in Section II.D above: 

  * to measure subscriber satisfaction 
  * to improve services and marketing 
  * to establish individual customer profiles for targeted advertising and customer retention purposes 

Information logged by the RCN network also is used by RCN to determine compliance with the RCN Internet Access Agreement, Acceptable Use Policy, and other applicable RCN policies and agreements. RCN may use information logged by the RCN network as necessary: 

  * to protect RCN rights or property 
  * to protect the RCN network from viruses, worms, and excessive spam 
  * to enforce RCN’s Internet Access Agreement, Acceptable Use Policy, and other RCN policies and agreements 

RCN also may disclose to third parties information logged by the RCN network and/or the contents of private communication over the Internet if RCN, in its sole discretion, reasonably believes that such action is necessary: 

  * to comply with applicable law or valid legal process, such as in the event RCN is served with a Subpoena, Court Order or other legal mandate, requiring the production of such records 
  * in emergencies when a person’s physical safety is at issue 

In addition, RCN reserves the right to disclose the identity of a subscriber, whether or not in conjunction with other information, to third parties as required to comply with applicable law, or valid legal process, or law enforcement request. 

**E. Billing**

All bills are mailed at regular intervals to the billing address indicated in RCN’s records to the attention of the account holder only. In order to perform the billing function, answer questions relating to billing, and collect on overdue accounts, RCN customer service representatives, credit, and collections representatives and billing personnel have access to the billing systems, which contain Personally Identifiable Information and CPNI. 

**F. Use of Information in Connection with Sale or Liquidation of RCN**

RCN reserves the right to provide customer lists and related information in connection with any contemplated sale of the company or of all or part of the business assets used to provide any RCN service to which the customers on a list subscribe, and to treat RCN customer information as a business asset in the event of bankruptcy or liquidation. 

**G. Data Retention**

Except as otherwise required by law or specifically described herein, RCN maintains its customers’ Personally Identifiable Information for the life of the customer’s account, plus an additional seven (7) years. Aggregated Data is retained by RCN for a period of up to seven (7) years. 

**IV. CUSTOMER AGREEMENT**

RCN will consider Personally Identifiable Information and CPNI that is collected and kept about any person to be confidential, and will disclose it to a third party only under the circumstances described within this Privacy Policy. Upon a customer's act of submitting such information to RCN, the customer acknowledges and agrees to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, and the customer shall indemnify, defend and hold harmless RCN, its parent company, agents, employees and subsidiaries, from and against any and all claims, loss, damage, cost or expense (including attorney's fees) to the extent such claims directly arise as a result RCN’s handling of customer’s information in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy. 

**V. LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES**

Our web site contains links to other web sites not operated by RCN, which may or may not have similar practices in place to protect the privacy of information that you supply. RCN encourages everyone to review the privacy statements of each of the sites that are linked to or accessed from RCN's web sites, so that you will understand how each visited site collects, uses, and distributes information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by web sites that we do not operate. In an effort to provide a diversity of service selections, RCN from time-to-time teams up with unaffiliated companies, for example in a co-branded web site. If information will be collected or maintained by any company other than RCN, that other company's privacy policy will govern the treatment of such information. 

**VI. REVISION OF THIS POLICY**

This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time by RCN, by updating the copy posted on the RCN web site(s). Amendments to this Privacy Policy will be effective when posted on the RCN web site(s). You should therefore periodically visit the Privacy Policy page on our web site to review the current Privacy Policy, so you are aware of any such revisions to which RCN's employees, agents and customers are bound. Revisions to RCN's Privacy Policy will be announced on RCN's homepage at [www.rcn.com ](http://www.rcn.com/). 

Love RCN! Always recommend it to friends and neighbors. 

Gwendolyn, Washington, DC

Award  
Winning

**2016**  
Overall  
Satisfaction

**2015**  
Top Consumer  
Recommended

**Readers Choice**  
3 Years  
in a Row

Reprinted from www.pcmag.com with permission. © 2017 Ziff Davis, LLC. All Rights Reserved.

### Switching Is Easy

With same-day installation, two-hour service windows and 24/7 customer support, switching to RCN has never been easier.
